(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
晩餐歌
作詞・作曲 tuki.
Bansanka
Lyrics & Composition by tuki.
君を泣かすから だから一緒には居れないな
I'll make you cry, so I can't stay with you.
君を泣かすから 早く忘れて欲しいんだ
I'll make you cry, so I want you to forget me quickly.
人間だからね たまには違うものも食べたいね
Since we're human, we want to eat something different once in a while.
君を泣かすから そう君を泣かすから
Because I'll make you cry, yes, I'll make you cry.
でも味気ないないないないんだよね
But it's so dull and tasteless.
会いたいなんなんだよね
I just want to see you.
君以外会いたくないんだよね
I don't want to see anyone but you.
なんて勝手だね
How selfish of me.
大体曖昧なんなんだよね
Everything is just so vague.
愛の存在証明なんて
Something like a proof of love's existence...
君が教えてくれないか
Won't you tell me?
何十回の夜を過ごしたって得られないような
Something I can't obtain even after spending dozens of nights...
愛してるを並べてみて
Try lining up "I love you"s.
何十回の夜を過ごしたって得られないような
Something I can't obtain even after spending dozens of nights...
最高のフルコースを頂戴
Give me the best full-course meal.
君を泣かすから きっと一生は無理だよね
I'll make you cry, so a lifetime together is probably impossible.
君を泣かすから 胸がとても痛むんだ
Because I'll make you cry, my heart aches so much.
人間だからね たまには分かり合えなくなって
Since we're human, sometimes we can't understand each other.
君を泣かすから また君を泣かすから
I'll make you cry, I'll make you cry again.
でも自信がないないないないんだよね
But I have no confidence at all.
変わりたくないないないないんだよね
I don't want to change at all.
でも 自信がないんだよね
But I lack confidence.
変わりたくないんだよね
I don't want to change.
君以外 会いたくないんだよね
I don't want to meet anyone but you.
なんて勝手だね
How selfish of me.
大体 曖昧だったよね
It was mostly ambiguous, wasn't it?
愛の存在証明なんて
A proof of the existence of love...
君がそこに居るのにね
...even though you are right there.
何百回の夜を過ごしたって
No matter how many hundreds of nights pass,
得られぬような愛してるを並べてみて
Try to line up 'I love yous' that can't be obtained.
何百回の夜を過ごしたって
No matter how many hundreds of nights pass,
得られぬような最高のフルコースを頂戴
Give me the best full-course meal that can't be obtained.
離れないで 傍に居てくれたのは
The one who didn't leave and stayed by my side...
結局 君一人だったよね
...was only you in the end.
涙のスパイスは 君の胸に
The spice of tears will likely remain...
残ってしまうだろうけど
...within your heart, though.
何千回の夜を過ごしたって
No matter how many thousands of nights pass,
得られぬような愛してるを並べるから
I'll line up 'I love yous' that can't be obtained.
何千回の夜を過ごしたって
No matter how many thousands of nights pass,
得られぬような最高のフルコースを
I'll give the best full-course meal that can't be obtained.
何万回の夜を過ごしたって
No matter how many tens of thousands of nights pass,
忘れぬような愛してるを並べるから
I'll line up unforgettable 'I love yous'.
何万回の夜を過ごしたって
No matter how many tens of thousands of nights pass,
忘れぬような最高のフルコースを頂戴
Give me an unforgettable, supreme full-course meal.
ぱずき！
Pazuki!
右手にマイク、左手に地図、
Mic in my right hand, map in my left,
あなたのハートをゼロゲッサー！
I'm a Zero-Guesser for your heart!
ということで、AZKiです！
So, I'm AZKi!
みんな、あこずきー、あこずきー！
Everyone, Akozuki, Akozuki!
本日は、AZKi活動6周年記念ライブ「百花繚乱」へお越しいただき、ありがとうございます！
Thank you for coming to AZKi's 6th Anniversary Live 'Hyakka Ryouran' today!
このね、今日のライブのタイトル「百花繚乱」はですね、色々な花が咲き乱れることということで...
The title of today's live, 'Hyakka Ryouran,' refers to various flowers blooming in profusion...
本当に今日は色んなことを詰め込んで、想いや内容、モリモリでお届けしていきたいと思います！
So today, I want to pack in all sorts of things and deliver a lot of feelings and content!
よろしくお願いします！
Please enjoy the show!
ということで、一曲目は「晩餐歌」でした。どうだったかな？
So, the first song was 'Bansanka.' How was it?
どうだった？どうだった？どうだった？
How was it? How was it? How was it?
はい。秋のね、こんな秋の夜に、なんか、しんみりと聴きたくなるバラードからお届けいたしました！
Yes. I started with a ballad that makes you want to listen quietly on an autumn night like this!
そしてそして、冒頭でも説明しましたが、今日は活動6周年！
And also, as I explained at the beginning, today is the 6th anniversary of my activities!
わーい！わーい！わーい！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay! Yay! Yay!
ということで、活動当初は、6年を迎えられるなんて本当にAZKi思っていませんでした。
To be honest, AZKi didn't think she would be able to celebrate 6 years when she first started.
今日、この日を迎えられることは、本当に、本当に応援してくれるみんながいるからです！
The fact that I can welcome this day is truly, truly because of all of you who support me!
本当に様々な分岐点を経て、このライブができることが、本当に、本当に嬉しいです！
After going through many turning points, I am truly, truly happy to be able to hold this live!
ありがとうございます！開拓者のみんな、ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you to all the Pioneers!
はい。次は、本日のハッシュタグの紹介です。
Next, I'll introduce today's hashtags.
今日のハッシュタグは、こちら！
Today's hashtags are these!
「#AZKi新衣装3Dライブ」ということで...
'#AZKiNewOutfit3DLive'...
え？待って。「新衣装3Dライブ」ってことは？
Wait. 'New Outfit 3D Live' means...?
はい、このあと、後半に新衣装のお披露目あります！
Yes, there will be a new outfit reveal in the second half!
ね、もうこのね、今キービジュアルがね、ほら、後ろに見えてますけれども。
As you can see, the key visual is already visible behind me.
これなのか？これなのか？
Is it this one? Is it this one?
どうなのか？ここまで言っといて違ったらどうしよう。ということで...
What do you think? What if I say all this and it's different? So...
新3D衣装も、お披露目もありますので、
Since there's also a new 3D outfit reveal,
よろしくお願いします！
please look forward to it!
お披露目のあとは、写真撮影タイムもあるので、たくさんスクショして、たくさんポストしてくれると嬉しいです！
After the reveal, there will be a photo time, so I'd be happy if you take lots of screenshots and post them!
もちろんライブの感想などのポストも、大大大歓迎です！
Of course, posts about your impressions of the live are also very, very welcome!
…上げです！
...thank you for the buildup!
はい。
Yes.
今日のね、ライブは前半は
Today's live, in the first half...
活動6年頑張ってきたあずきのご褒美的な感じで
as a sort of reward for AZKi, who has worked hard for 6 years of activity,
本当に本当にやりたいことを詰め込みました。
I packed in the things I really, really wanted to do.
欲張りセットな感じで。
It's like a greedy set.
そして、後半はね、今回キービジュアルからもわかるかもしれませんが
And then, for the second half, as you might tell from the key visual,
ちょっと和風、和風なコンセプトでお届けしたいと思います！
I'd like to deliver it with a slightly Japanese-style concept!
この後は、ゲストが登場するのでお楽しみに！
After this, a guest will appear, so please look forward to it!
それでは、コラボパートどうぞ！
Well then, here is the collaboration part!
神っぽいな
作詞・作曲 ピノキオピー
God-ish
Lyrics & Composition: PinocchioP
Oh my god
愛のネタバレ「別れ」っぽいな
Spoilers of love, it's like a "breakup"
人生のネタバレ「死ぬ」っぽいな
Spoilers of life, it's like "dying"
なにそれ意味深でかっこいいじゃん…
What's that? It's so meaningful and cool...
それっぽい単語集で踊ってんだ
Dancing with a collection of words like that
死刑
Death Penalty
とぅる　とぅる　とぅる　"風"　ぽいじゃん　ぽいじゃん
Tu-ru tu-ru tu-ru, like the "wind", like it, like it
とぅる　とぅる　とぅる　"風"　とぅる　とぅる　とぅる
Tu-ru tu-ru tu-ru, like the "wind", tu-ru tu-ru tu-ru
神っぽいな
God-ish
もういいぜ　もういいぜ　それもういいぜ
Enough already, enough already, that's enough already
もういいぜ　逆に興奮してきたなあ
Enough already, I'm actually starting to get excited
おっきいね　おっきいね　夢おっきいね
It's big, it's big, the dream is big
景気いいけど品性はジ・エンド　うえいうえいうえい
Business is good but dignity is the end, yay yay yay
Gott ist tot
God is dead
神っぽいな　それ　卑怯
God-ish, that's unfair
神っぽいな　それ　"My God"
God-ish, that's "My God"
アイウォンチュー　ウォンチュー　IQが下がっていく感じ
I want you, want you, the feeling of IQ dropping
邪心っぽいな　それ　卑怯
Evil-ish, that's unfair
邪心っぽいな　それ　"I hate you"
Evil-ish, that's "I hate you"
アイヘイチュー　ヘイチュー　害虫はどっち
I hate you, I hate you, which one is the pest?
その髪型　その目　その口元　その香水　その服　そのメイク
That hairstyle, those eyes, that mouth, that perfume, those clothes, that makeup
アレっぽいな　それ　卑怯　アレっぽいな　それ　ぽいな
It's like that, that's unfair, it's like that, that's like that
その名言　その意見　その批評　そのカリスマ　そのギャグ　そのセンス
That quote, that opinion, that criticism, that charisma, that gag, that sense
神っぽいな　それ　卑怯　ぽいな　ぽいな　ぽい　あこがれちゃうわ
God-ish, that's unfair, like that, like that, like that, I'm longing for it
とぅる　とぅる　とぅる　"風"　ぽいじゃん　ぽいじゃん
Tu-ru tu-ru tu-ru, like the "wind", like it, like it
とぅる　とぅる　とぅる　"風"　とぅる　とぅる　とぅる
Tu-ru tu-ru tu-ru, like the "wind", tu-ru tu-ru tu-ru
神っぽいな
God-ish
メタ思考する本質は悪意
The essence of meta-thinking is malice
人を小馬鹿にしたようなそくい
A prompt that seems to make light of people
無為に生き延びるのは難しい
It's difficult to survive for nothing
権力に呑まれて揺らぐ灯
A flickering light swallowed by power
神を否定し神になり代わり
Denying God and taking God's place
玉座で豹変する小物たち
Small fry who change suddenly on the throne
批判に見せかけ自戒の祈り
A prayer of self-restraint disguised as criticism
Do you know?
何言ってんの？　それ　ウザい
What are you saying? That's annoying
何言ってんの？　それ　意味がよくわかんないし
What are you saying? I don't really get the meaning
眠っちゃうよ　マジ
I'm gonna fall asleep, seriously
飽きっぽいんだ　オーケー　みんな　飽きっぽいんだ　オーケー
Fickle, okay everyone, fickle, okay
踊れるやつ　ちょうだい　ちょうだい　ビーム
Give me something I can dance to, give me, give me, beam
きしょいね　きしょいね　それきしょいね
Gross, gross, that's gross
逆にファンになってきたじゃん
Actually, I've become a fan
ちっちゃいね　ちっちゃいね　つわちっちゃいね
Small, small, the vessel is small
天才ゆえ孤独ですね　かっけぇ…　かっけぇ…
Lonely because of genius, right? So cool... so cool...
Gott ist tot
God is dead
神っぽいな　それ　卑怯
God-ish, that's unfair
神っぽいな　それ　"My God"
God-ish, that's "My God"
超健康　健康　言い張って　くたばっていく感じ
Insisting on super health, health, feeling like dying
やけっぽいな　それ　卑怯
Desperate-ish, that's unfair
やけっぽいな　それ　"My God"
Desperate-ish, that's "My God"
もう哀愁　哀愁　エピゴーネンのヒール
Already sorrow, sorrow, the heel of an epigone
そのタイトル　その絵　そのストーリー　その音楽　その歌　そのメロディ
That title, that art, that story, that music, that song, that melody
アレっぽいな　それ　アレっぽいな　それ　ぽいな
It's like that, that, it's like that, that, like that
その名言　その意見　その批評　そのカリスマ　そのギャグ　そのセンス
That quote, that opinion, that criticism, that charisma, that gag, that sense
神っぽいな　それ　卑怯　ぽいな　ぽいな　ぽい　あこがれちゃうわ！
God-ish, that's unfair, like that, like that, like that, I'm longing for it!
とぅる　とぅる　とぅる　"風"　ぽいじゃん　ぽいじゃん
Tu-ru tu-ru tu-ru, like the "wind", like it, like it
とぅる　とぅる　とぅる　"風"　とぅる　とぅる　とぅる
Tu-ru tu-ru tu-ru, like the "wind", tu-ru tu-ru tu-ru
神っぽいな
God-ish
愛のネタバレ「別れ」っぽいな
Spoilers of love, it's like a "breakup"
人生のネタバレ「死ぬ」っぽいな
Spoilers of life, it's like "dying"
すべて理解して患った
Understood everything and became ill
無邪気に踊っていたかった人生
I wanted to dance innocently, life
ネコカプリーナ
作詞・作曲 堀江ヒロキ / キノオピー
Neko Capurina
Lyrics & Composition: Hiroki Horie / Kino-P
生の本音はえぐいから
Raw true feelings are gross
ちゃんと火を通して食べてね
Make sure to cook it through before eating
リップサービスは狡いかな
Is lip service unfair?
それも威信で死のれレシピ
That's also a dying recipe with prestige
みんなどう、自不一致思ってるかい？
How about everyone, do you think self-discrepancy?
嘘の万国博覧会
A world expo of lies
みんなどう、自不一致思ってるかい？
How about everyone, do you think self-discrepancy?
痛みを飼いならせ
Tame the pain
...して
...do.
嫌いだけど好き まずくても美味しい
I hate it but I like it, even if it's bad, it's delicious.
着ぐるみを着てハグしてあげる
I'll put on a costume and give you a hug.
泣かせないように 怒らせないように
So as not to make you cry, so as not to make you angry.
丁度良く君と遊びたいのだ
I just want to play with you perfectly.
ネコカブリーノ ネコカブリーノ
Neko-kaburino Neko-kaburino
ちょっと臆病な君が好き
I like you, who is a little cowardly.
ネコカブリーノ ネコカブリーノ
Neko-kaburino Neko-kaburino
取り繕ってる僕が好き
I like myself, who is keeping up appearances.
陽射しを浴びてる君が好きだよ
I like you, who is bathed in sunlight.
表と裏では大違い
A big difference between the front and the back.
建前も本音も要領次第
Both public stance and true feelings depend on the knack.
みんな自分疑ってるかい？
Is everyone doubting themselves?
ひとりぼっちの音楽隊
A lonely musical band.
みんな自分疑ってるかい？
Is everyone doubting themselves?
首輪の鈴ならして
Ring the bell on the collar.
最悪だけどハッピー しんどくても平気
It's the worst but I'm happy, even if it's tough, I'm fine.
あべこべな夢を見せてあげる
I'll show you a topsy-turvy dream.
傷つけないように 追い詰めないように
So as not to hurt you, so as not to corner you.
夜明けまで君とふざけ合うのだ
We'll fool around together until dawn.
ネコカブリーノ ネコカブリーノ
Neko-kaburino Neko-kaburino
爪を丸めてる君が好き
I like you, who is retracting your claws.
ネコカブリーノ ネコカブリーノ
Neko-kaburino Neko-kaburino
涙を見せない僕が好き
I like myself, who doesn't show tears.
痛みを知ってる君が好きだよ
I like you, who knows pain.
君は猫 猫 ファスナー付きの猫
You're a cat, a cat, a cat with a zipper.
君は人 人 ファスナー付きの人
You're a person, a person, a person with a zipper.
あれはUFO UFO ファスナー付きのUFO
That's a UFO, a UFO, a UFO with a zipper.
君は猫 猫 ファスナー付きの猫
You're a cat, a cat, a cat with a zipper.
君は人 人 ファスナー付きの人
You're a person, a person, a person with a zipper.
あれはUFO UFO ファスナー付きのUFO
That's a UFO, a UFO, a UFO with a zipper.
君は誰 誰 特別な人
Who are you, who? A special person.
ネコカブリーノ ネコカブリーノ
Neko-kaburino Neko-kaburino
ちょっと臆病な君が好き
I like you, who is a little cowardly.
君も僕も馴染めない世界で
In a world where neither you nor I can fit in.
やっと見つけた居場所だから
Because it's the place I finally found.
ネコカブリーノ ネコカブリーノ
Neko-kaburino Neko-kaburino
取り繕ってる僕が好き
I like myself, who is keeping up appearances.
君も僕もどこか失くしてる世界で
In a world where both you and I have lost something.
明日もまた会えたらいいな
I hope we can meet again tomorrow.
ネコカブリーノ ネコカブリーノ
Neko-kaburino Neko-kaburino
陽射しを浴びてる君が好きだよ
I like you, who is bathed in sunlight.
ぺこらんだむぶれいん！
Peko Ran Damu Brain!
乱々 乱舞 さあ 叫んじゃえわ
Ran-ran boisterous dance, now, let's scream.
事件だ 毎日大変
It's an incident, every day is tough.
大成功のタネだと
They say it's the seed of great success.
笑えない 冗談 笑え
A joke you can't laugh at, laugh.
ぺこらんだむぶれいん！
Peko Ran Damu Brain!
ぺこらんだむ しちゃいなまえ
Do the Peko Ran Damu.
NO NO NO 知れ 蒸し返せ そりゃ
NO NO NO, know it, rake it up.
NAN NAN NAN 知れ 乱々 乱々
NAN NAN NAN, know it, Ran-ran Ran-ran.
NO NO NO 知れ 蒸し返せ そりゃ
NO NO NO, know it, rake it up.
受け取り拒否ですぞ
Refusal to receive.
難題 意外な 立ち上が
Difficult problem, unexpected standing up.
ギュンとプロペラ 回れ
Spin the propeller with a whir.
どこへ？ 疑わしい？ 知らない 知らないんだ
Where to? Suspicious? I don't know, I really don't know.
ほら 世界は繋がっちゃう 繋がっちゃう
Look, the world will connect, it will connect.
境界越えたらきっかけ
If you cross the boundary, it's the trigger.
それに会いたいって 思うんだ
I think I want to meet that.
そんなの どうでも いいじゃん いいじゃん
That doesn't matter, it's fine, it's fine.
退屈 嫌だったら こっち来れば
If you hate boredom, come over here.
大事な場所なんてさ 自分で作らなくちゃ
You have to make your own important place.
これが 絶景だ どうだ どうだ どうだ
This is a superb view, how about it, how about it?
ありがた迷惑か
Is it an unwelcome favor?
乱々 乱舞 びっくりだわ
Ran-ran boisterous dance, it's a surprise.
生きてりゃ 毎日大変
Every day is tough if you're alive.
大問題の跡には 楽しいことあるかな
After a big problem, I wonder if there will be something fun.
乱々 乱舞 叫んじゃえわ
Ran-ran boisterous dance, let's scream.
事件だ 毎日大変
It's an incident, every day is tough.
大成功のタネだと
They say it's the seed of great success.
笑えない 冗談 笑え
A joke you can't laugh at, laugh.
ぺこらんだむぶれいん！
Peko Ran Damu Brain!
ぺこらんだむ しちゃいなまえ
Do the Peko Ran Damu.
NO NO NO 知れ 蒸し返せ そりゃ
NO NO NO, know it, rake it up.
NO NO NO 知れ 乱々 乱々
NO NO NO, know it, Ran-ran Ran-ran.
NO NO NO 知れ 蒸し返せ そりゃ
NO NO NO, know it, rake it up.
受け取り拒否ですぞ
Refusal to receive.
どんな 空でも ヒウィゴー
Any sky, here we go.
くるん た期待が 回る
The spinning expectations turn.
どっちが 地面とか 知らない 知りたくない
I don't know which is the ground, I don't want to know.
待たせしてるデヘペロ言葉
I've kept you waiting, tehe-pero words.
だーれも並びませんでした
Nobody was standing in line
だれか「会いたい」っていってよね
Someone, please say "I want to see you"
うれしかったからね
Because I'd be so happy
やっほー やっほー
Yahoo, yahoo
冒険ラブならこっちこれぼ
If you love adventure, come this way
まずは一歩目からだ
First, take the first step
千里はちょっと無理だろ
A thousand miles is a bit much, right?
やばい！ 本音が
Oh no! My true feelings...
待って！待って！待って！
Wait! Wait! Wait!
思わずできちゃったよ
I accidentally did it
ぺこらんだむぶれいん！
Pekorandum Brain!
めちゃくちゃやってみるか
Shall we do something crazy?
大混乱も大好き
I love big chaos, too
楽しいなら大好き
If it's fun, I love it
ぺこらんだむぶれいん！
Pekorandum Brain!
歌っちゃえば
If you just sing it out
まだまだやっちゃうかな
I guess I'll keep going
大旋風巻き起こせ
Stir up a massive whirlwind
笑え　明日も笑え
Smile, smile tomorrow too
ぺこらんだむぶれいん！
Pekorandum Brain!
ぺこらんだむしっちょいまい
Pekorandum s-choi-mai
脳がなんか伝えたがる
My brain wants to tell you something
変われ変われ世界中
Change, change, the whole world
景色を変えるために
To change the scenery
みんな　みんな　聞こえるかい
Can everyone, everyone hear me?
聞こえるかい！
Can you hear me?!
ぺこらんだむぶれいん！
Pekorandum Brain!
びっくりだわ
I'm so surprised
生きてりゃ　毎日大変
When you're alive, every day is tough
大混乱の後には
After a big chaos
楽しいことあるから
There's something fun waiting
ぺこらんだむぶれいん！
Pekorandum Brain!
叫んじゃえば
If you just scream it out
事件だ　毎日大変
It's an incident, every day is tough
大成功の種だと
It's a seed of great success
笑えないときゃ笑え
When you can't smile, just smile
ぺこらんだむぶれいん！
Pekorandum Brain!
ぺこらんだむしっちょいまい
Pekorandum s-choi-mai
ぺこらんだむぶれいん！
Pekorandum Brain!
ぺこらんだむのののいえーい
Pekorandum no-no-no yeah
はい、ということで、ゲストのお二人のオリ曲を中心に3曲お送りいたしました。
All right, so we just performed three songs, centered around the original songs of our two guests.
そしてね、ブライト衣装に着替えて参りました。スカートブライト衣装！
And I've changed into my "Bright" costume. This is the skirted version of the Bright costume!
ということで、お送りした曲のね、ちょっと感想なんかも言っていこうかなと思います。
So, I'd like to share some of my thoughts on the songs we performed.
まず「神っぽいな」。今回ね、どうしてもこの3人で歌ってみたくて。
First was "God-ish." I really wanted to try singing it with these three people.
おかゆんとぺこちゃんをお呼びいたしました。
So I invited Okayun and Peko-chan.
なんか、なかなかダークなAZKi、こういうライブの曲あんまりやっていないなと思って。
I felt like I haven't done many live songs with a dark AZKi vibe like that.
ちょっといつもよりダークな感じで、もう、すごくすごく、歌詞割りも、歌詞のパート分けも、めちゃくちゃ悩みながら。
It had a darker feel than usual, and I really, really struggled with the line distribution and part assignments.
このぺこちゃんに歌ってもらうにはどこがいいかな？とか、おかゆんに歌ってもらうのはどこがいいかな？とか、
I was wondering things like, "Which part would be best for Peko-chan?" or "Which part would suit Okayun?"
すごく夜な夜な考えて、この「神っぽいな」お届けいたしました。
I stayed up night after night thinking about it before bringing you "God-ish."
どうだった？もうめちゃくちゃ歌も難しかったから、すごくすごく、ダンスもダンスもみんなでね、頑張りました。
How was it? The song was incredibly difficult, so we all worked really, really hard on the dance, too.
どうだったかな？
What did you think?
はい、そして次は、おかゆんのオリ曲「猫かぶり」。
Yes, and next was Okayun's original song, "Nekokaburi."
これはずっとずっと、AZKiがおかゆんと一緒に歌って踊りたかった曲でして。
This is a song that I've wanted to sing and dance to with Okayun for a very, very long time.
もう振り付けも可愛いじゃん。この、もうめちゃくちゃ可愛くて、おかゆん一緒に歌ってくれる？ってお誘いしたところ、
The choreography is just so cute, right? It's super cute, and when I asked Okayun if she'd sing it with me...
一緒に歌ってくれました。
She agreed to do it.
そして、なんと、皆さんね、オカニャ、オカニャも登場してくれました。
And surprisingly, everyone, Okanya—Okanya showed up too!
もうAZKiがどうしてもどうしても、オカニャ、もうおかゆんにずっとオカニャの良さについて、えーと語っていたんですけれども。
I've been telling Okayun all about how great Okanya is for the longest time.
今回満を持して、オカニャにも登場していただきました。
And this time, at last, we were able to have Okanya join us.
ということで、AZKiのすごい、あの、やりたいことをね、このパートでちょっと詰め込んでみました。
So, I packed a lot of things I really wanted to do into this section.
おカニャとも一緒に踊れたし、めちゃくちゃ幸せな6周年を迎えております、ということで、「猫かぶり」でございました。
I got to dance with Okanya, and I'm having an incredibly happy 6th anniversary. That was "Nekokaburi."
そして次は「ぺこらんだむぶれいん」。
And next was "Pekorandum Brain."
もうこれね、ぺこちゃんの曲の中で、AZKiもすんごいすんごいずっとずっとずっとずっと大好きで。
Out of all of Peko-chan's songs, I've loved this one for a very, very long time.
いつかぺこちゃんと一緒に歌いたい歌いたい歌いたいと思っていたので、
I'd always, always wanted to sing it with Peko-chan someday...
今回ね、ぺこちゃんの曲をぺこちゃんと一緒に歌えて幸せでございます。
So I'm so happy I could sing Peko-chan's song with her this time.
せっかくなので、ライブだから、うさ耳をつけてね。
Since it's a live concert, I even wore rabbit ears.
やっぱうさ耳をつけてぺこちゃんと一緒に歌う、踊る、みたいな。
Singing and dancing with Peko-chan while wearing rabbit ears was just the best.
…ようなことしたかったので、どうだったでしょうか？
...I wanted to do something like that, so how was it?
そっか！
I see!
いやあ、めちゃくちゃ今日はね、百花繚乱ということで、
Wow, today's theme is "Hyakka Ryouran,"
いろんな花が咲き乱れていきました！
so many different flowers were blooming in full glory!
ということで…
And so...
えー、次は皆さんお待たせいたしました、
Next, everyone, sorry for the wait...
新衣装をお披露目していきたいと思います！
I'd like to show you my new outfit!
えー、曲中に、なんと大、大、大、大変身しちゃいますので、
During the song, I'm going to undergo a big, big, big transformation...
お楽しみに！
Look forward to it!
それでは、
So now,
次の曲、どうぞ！
The next song, please enjoy!
大胆不敵にハイカラ革命
Daring and fearless, a high-collar revolution
磊々落々反戦国家
Open and aboveboard, an anti-war nation
日の丸印の二輪車転がし
Rolling a bicycle with the Hinomaru mark
悪霊退散 ICBM
Exorcising evil spirits, ICBM
環状線を走り抜けて
Running through the loop line
東奔西走なんのその
Running east and west, what of it?
少年少女戦国無双
Boys and girls, peerless in the warring states
浮世の随に
At the mercy of the transient world
千本桜 夜に紛れ
A thousand cherry blossoms, vanishing into the night
君の声も届かないよ
Even your voice won't reach
此処は宴 鋼の檻
Here is a banquet, a steel cage
その断頭台で見下ろして
Looking down from that guillotine
三千世界 常世の闇
Three thousand worlds, the darkness of the afterlife
嘆く唄も聞こえないよ
The song of lament won't be heard either
青藍の空 遥か彼方
The indigo sky, far, far away
その光線銃で打ち抜いて
Shoot through with that ray gun
百戦錬磨の見た目は将校
Veteran of a hundred battles, looking like an officer
いったりきたりの花魁道中
Coming and going, the courtesan procession
アイツもコイツも皆で集まれ
Him and her, everyone gather around
聖者の行進 1 2 3 4
The march of the saints, 1 2 3 4
禅定門を潜り抜けて
Passing through the gate of meditation
安楽浄土 厄払い
The Pure Land of Bliss, warding off evil
きっと最後は大団円
Surely the end will be a grand finale
拍手の合間に
Amidst the applause
千本桜 夜に紛れ
A thousand cherry blossoms, vanishing into the night
君の声も届かないよ
Even your voice won't reach
此処は宴 鋼の檻
Here is a banquet, a steel cage
その断頭台で見下ろして
Looking down from that guillotine
三千世界 常世の闇
Three thousand worlds, the darkness of the afterlife
嘆く唄も聞こえないよ
The song of lament won't be heard either
希望の丘 遥か彼方
The hill of hope, far, far away
その閃光弾を打ち上げろ
Launch that flash grenade
環状線を走り抜けて
Running through the loop line
東奔西走なんのその
Running east and west, what of it?
少年少女戦国無双
Boys and girls, peerless in the warring states
浮世の随に
At the mercy of the transient world
千本桜 夜に紛れ
A thousand cherry blossoms, vanishing into the night
君の声も届かないよ
Even your voice won't reach
此処は宴 鋼の檻
Here is a banquet, a steel cage
その断頭台を飛び降りて
Jump down from that guillotine
千本桜 夜に紛れ
A thousand cherry blossoms, vanishing into the night
君が歌い僕は踊る
You sing and I dance
此処は宴 鋼の檻
Here is a banquet, a steel cage
さあ光線銃を打ちまくれ
Now, fire that ray gun like crazy
はい、ということでお送りしたのは千本桜でした！
Yes, and that was "Senbonzakura"!
はい！じゃん！
Yes! Ta-da!
なんと、こちらが新衣装、3D新衣装でございます！
Surprisingly, this is the new outfit, my new 3D outfit!
なんと、和、お正月衣装となっております！
Amazingly, it's a Japanese, New Year's outfit!
さきほど、千本桜の曲に合わせて、サクラで衣装チェンジしました！
I just changed into this Sakura outfit to match the song "Senbonzakura"!
こちらは今年ね、お正月に公開している衣装で、
This is the outfit I revealed this past New Year, and...
3Dのお披露目は今日が初めてになります！
...today is its 3D debut!
いかがでしょうか？すごい可愛いでしょ？
What do you think? It's really cute, right?
はい！そして、お披露目はなんと、これだけじゃないんです！
Yes! And that's not the only debut!
呼び込みたいと思います！開拓者ー！
I'd like to call it out! Kaitakusha!
わー！ということでなんと、なんと、なんと！
Wow! So, surprisingly, surprisingly, surprisingly!
えー開拓者がお正月衣装、可愛いー！
Um, Kaitakusha is in a New Year's outfit, so cute!
わー！なんとね、このAZKiの今回の新衣装に合わせて、
Wow! To match AZKi's new outfit this time,
開拓者もね、おめかししてもらいましたー！
Kaitakusha has also gotten dressed up!
色んなね、開拓者動きができるって聞いてるんで、披露してもらおうかな！
I heard it can do various movements, so let's have it show them off!
じゃあ、AZKiのこと応援して！
Then, cheer for AZKi!
おめでとう！ペンライト持ってくれてる！
Congratulations! It's holding penlights!
そして、じゃあAZKiの...開拓者のマーク、おーしま！
And then, AZKi's... The Kaitakusha mark, "O-shima"!
あ、ちゃんと出るんだね、ハンマーとつるはし、持ってますね。
Oh, they really come out! It's holding a hammer and a pickaxe.
そして、あーそうだね、開拓者くん、やっぱさ、秋だよね。
And, oh right, Kaitakusha-kun, it's autumn, after all.
AZKiと一緒に紅葉見に行こうよ。笑え！
Let's go see the autumn leaves with AZKi. Laugh!
笑ってくれた、ありがとう、ありがとう！
It laughed for me, thank you, thank you!
ということで、あ、すごい喜んでるね、喜んでるね。
So, oh, it's so happy, it's happy.
このちょっとお正月仕様になった開拓者でございます。
This is the Kaitakusha in New Year's style.
可愛いね、髪飾りと、注連縄。お正月感満載なんですけれども。
Cute hair ornament, and shimenawa rope. Full of New Year vibes.
お正月開拓者と一緒に写真を撮りたいと思いまーす！
I'd like to take some photos with the New Year Kaitakusha!
はい、みんなスクショタイムだよ！
Okay, everyone, it's screenshot time!
じゃあれ、えーっと、開拓者マーク！
Then, um, the Kaitakusha mark!
あ、ありがとう！この開拓者もいいですね。
Oh, thank you! This Kaitakusha is good too.
じゃあ、あとペンライト、ペンライト！
And then, penlights, penlights!
あ、ペンライトの開拓者！
Oh, Kaitakusha with penlights!
はい、みんな撮れた？お正月のAZKiと開拓者でございます。
Alright, did everyone get the shots? It's AZKi and Kaitakusha in New Year's style.
ということで、じゃあステージの中央に戻りまして、
So, let's head back to the center of the stage.
ここからもスクショタイムということで、みんなスクショしていってね！
It's screenshot time from here too, so everyone, take some screenshots!
袖をね、こうやっていっぱい広げていたので、
I was spreading out my sleeves like this, so...
どうでしょう、どうでしょう。可愛い衣装。
How's this? A cute outfit.
そして、ちょっと振り向きとかしちゃうぞ。
And I'll even do a little turn-around.
はっ、と、この、この角度どうですか？どうでしょうか。
Ha! How's this, this angle? What do you think?
あ、普通に可愛くピースしよう。ピース！どうかな？
Oh, let's just do a cute peace sign. Peace! How's that?
え、撮れてる？あ、ありがとう！
Oh, are you getting it? Oh, thank you!
そして、こう、ちょっと手を広げたりしちゃったりして。
And, let's see, I'll spread my hands out a bit.
一緒にお正月な感じ。
A New Year feel together.
細かいところみんなに見てほしいなと思うので、カメラマンさん！
I want everyone to see the finer details, so Mr. Cameraman!
このね、可愛いブーツと、この袴の可愛い柄と、
These cute boots, and the cute pattern of this hakama...
あとね、この袖のピンクの可愛い柄になってます。後ろはこんな感じ。
...and also this cute pink pattern on the sleeves. The back looks like this.
ベレー帽も可愛いでしょ？髪飾りも。可愛くお仕立ていただきましたー！
The beret is cute too, right? The hair ornament too. They were made so cutely!
この後、面限で余すことなくお見せいたしますので、
I'll show everything to you later in the members-only stream...
気になった方はぜひこの後の面限のライブもよろしくお願いします！
...so if you're interested, please join the members-only live stream!
はい！ということで、ここからはこの新衣装に合わせて、
Yes! So, from here on, to match this new outfit...
和風コンセプトで、和テイストな曲をお届けしていきたいと思います！
...I'd like to perform some Japanese-style songs with a Japanese concept!
この後はちょっと曲に合わせて
After this, following the songs,
衣装もちょっとずつ何かが変化していったりするので
something about the outfit will gradually change,
お楽しみにしててください！
so please look forward to it!
それでは、次の曲へどうぞ！
Now then, on to the next song!
檄!帝国華撃団
Geki! Teikoku Kagekidan
引き裂いた 闇が吠え
The torn darkness howls
震える帝都に
In the trembling Imperial Capital
愛の歌 高らかに
A song of love rings out loud
躍り出る戦士たち
The warriors leap out to dance
心まで 鋼鉄に
Even their hearts are made of steel
武装する乙女
The maidens arm themselves
悪を蹴散らして
Kicking aside all evil
正義を示すのだ
To demonstrate their justice
走れ 光速の 帝国華撃団
Run, light-speed Imperial Flower Assault Troop
唸れ 衝撃の 帝国華撃団
Roar, high-impact Imperial Flower Assault Troop
私たち、正義のために戦います。
We fight for the sake of justice.
たとえそれが、命を懸ける戦いであっても。
Even if it is a battle where we risk our lives.
私たちは一歩も引きません。
We will not back down a single step.
それが、帝国華撃団なのです！
For that is the Imperial Flower Assault Troop!
街の灯が 消え果てて
The lights of the city fade away
怯える帝都に
In the frightened Imperial Capital
虹の色 染め上げて
Dyeing everything in rainbow colors
躍り出る戦士たち
The warriors leap out to dance
暁に 激情を
In the dawn, the passion
照らし出す乙女
Illuminates the maidens
悪を滅ぼして
Annihilating all evil
正義を示すのだ
To demonstrate their justice
走れ 光速の 帝国華撃団
Run, light-speed Imperial Flower Assault Troop
唸れ 衝撃の 帝国華撃団
Roar, high-impact Imperial Flower Assault Troop
走れ 光速の 帝国華撃団
Run, light-speed Imperial Flower Assault Troop
唸れ 衝撃の 帝国華撃団
Roar, high-impact Imperial Flower Assault Troop
子供の頃の夢は
The dreams I had as a child
色褪せない落書きで
Are doodles that never fade away
思うまま書き滑らせて
I let my pen glide as I please
描く未来へと繋がる
Connecting to the future I draw
夢想歌
Musouka
澄み渡る空
The clear, sprawling sky
果てしないほど青く
Is endlessly blue
無邪気な心に
Into my innocent heart
満たされ 惹かれてく
It fills me and draws me in
やがて自由に飛び回れる
Soon, I will be able to fly freely
羽を手に入れて
Once I obtain my wings
垢抜けない瞳は
These unsophisticated eyes
追い求めてる 空の向こうへ行きたいな
Want to go beyond the sky they seek
止めどない願いから
If among my endless wishes
一つだけ叶うのなら
Only one could come true,
誰にも譲りたくはない
It's the one I'd never give up
夢を掴みたいと思うよ
I want to grasp my dream
子供の頃の夢は
The dreams I had as a child
色褪せない落書きで
Are doodles that never fade away
いつまでも書き続けられた
I could keep writing forever
願う未来へと繋がる
Connecting to the future I wish for
夢想歌
Musouka
鐘が鳴る音
The sound of a ringing bell...
遠くから聞こえてくる
...is heard from far away.
素直な心に
To an honest heart...
届いては響いてる
...it reaches and echoes.
光は七色に変わって
The light turns into seven colors...
弧を描いていく
...and draws an arc.
無垢な瞳は求めてく
Pure eyes are searching...
虹の向こうへ行きたいな
...wishing to go beyond the rainbow.
止めどなく願うほど
The more endlessly I wish...
忘れないでいたいこと
...the more things there are I want to never forget.
支えてくれる人がいて
Because there are people who support me...
夢を見ることができるから
...I am able to dream.
子供の頃の夢は
Dreams from childhood...
色褪せない落書きで
...are like graffiti that never fades.
想うまま書き滑らせて
Letting my thoughts flow as I write...
描く未来へと繋がる
...they connect to the future I draw.
やがて自由に飛び回れる
Eventually, I'll be able to fly around freely...
羽を手に入れて
...after I get my wings.
無垢な瞳は求めてく
Pure eyes are searching...
空の向こうへ行きたいな
...wishing to go beyond the sky.
止めどない願いから
From an endless wish...
一つだけ叶うのなら
...if only one could come true...
誰にも譲りたくはない
...I wouldn't want to give it up to anyone.
夢を掴みたいと思うよ
I want to grab that dream.
止めどなく願うほど
The more endlessly I wish...
忘れないでいたいこと
...the more things there are I want to never forget.
支えてくれる人がいて
Because there are people who support me...
夢を見ることができるから
...I am able to dream.
子供の頃の夢は
Dreams from childhood...
色褪せない落書きで
...are like graffiti that never fades.
想うまま書き滑らせて
Letting my thoughts flow as I write...
描く未来へと繋がる
...they connect to the future I draw.
せーの！
One, two!
1, 2, 3, はい！
1, 2, 3, go!
回レ! 雪月花
Maware! Setsugetsuka
ホイ！
Hoi!
よーっ、ポン！
Yoo, pon!
これがこれ位 咲き増すのは
This is blooming to this extent...
傾く者たちの栄華盛衰
...the rise and fall of those who stand out.
時代は常に日進月歩
The times are always progressing by leaps and bounds.
聞いて極楽 厄落とし
Hear it and reach paradise, a purification of bad luck.
一見は勧善懲悪
At first glance, it's the promotion of virtue and punishment of vice.
悪者共を一刀両断
Cutting through all the bad guys with one stroke.
でも本当はそれだけって
But is that really all it is?
アンタたちのモノなのさ
It's just what you all have.
もー何だか蒟蒻問答
A pointless argument.
よーっ、ポン！
Yoo, pon!
どこからともなく現れて
Appearing out of nowhere...
すぐどこか行っちゃって
...and disappearing again soon.
正真正銘の神出鬼没
Truly elusive and unpredictable.
一難去って また一難
Out of the frying pan and into the fire.
青春 追い掛ければ
If you chase after youth...
東奔西走
...you'll be running all over the place.
時代は常に千客万来
The times are always busy with many guests.
人の心は徒花か
Are people's hearts short-lived blossoms?
本気でそんなこと言ってんの？
Are you really saying such things?
もー全く奇想天外
It's completely unexpected.
たどり辿って夜の街
Going round and round in the city at night...
迷い一つなく踊りだす
...you start dancing without any hesitation.
はぁ！
Haa!
回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ
Spin, spin, spin, spin!
華麗に花弁 散らすように
Like petals scattering elegantly.
回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ
Spin, spin, spin, spin!
髪も振り乱して
With your hair flying wildly.
昨日、今日、明日、明後日、明々後日と
Yesterday, today, tomorrow, the day after, and the day after that...
この宴は続く
...this banquet will continue.
踊れ、歌え、一心不乱に回レ！
Dance, sing, spin with total focus!
今宵は雪月花
Tonight is a scene of snow, moon, and flowers.
よーっ、ポン！
Yoo, pon!
この世に平安訪れるの
May peace visit this world...
無礼講出し 象徴発信
...sending out symbols of freedom.
猛者共 戦国万来
Warriors everywhere, like a chaotic war era.
ひしめき合う 幽玄境
Crowding together in a mysterious realm.
努力するか 一攫千金
Will you work hard or try to strike it rich?
気が付いたら絶体絶命
Before you know it, you're in a desperate situation.
はぁ 本音のトコどうなってんの？
Haa, what's the truth of the matter?
もー全く奇想天外
It's completely unexpected.
たどり辿って夜の街
Going round and round in the city at night...
迷い一つなく踊りだす
...you start dancing without any hesitation.
はぁ！
Haa!
回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ
Spin, spin, spin, spin!
華麗に花弁 散らすように
Like petals scattering elegantly.
回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ
Spin, spin, spin, spin!
回レ！回レ！回レ！回レ！回レ！回レ！回レ！回レ！回レ！
Spin! Spin! Spin! Spin! Spin! Spin! Spin! Spin! Spin!
髪も振り乱して
With hair flying wildly
一昨日、昨日、今日と明日と明後日と
The day before yesterday, yesterday, today, tomorrow, and the day after
この宴は続く
This banquet continues
踊レ、歌エ、一心不乱に回レ
Dance, sing, spin with all your heart
今宵は雪月花
Tonight is Setsugetsuka
ハッ、ハッ、ハッ、ハッ、ハッ、ハッ、ハッ、ハッ
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha!
ハイッヤ！
Hai-ya!
ハッ、ハッ、ハッ、ハッ
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha!
ソレソレソレソレ！
Sore sore sore sore!
ハッ、ハッ、ハッ、ハッ、ハッ、ハッ、ハッ、ハッ
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha!
ハイッヤ！
Hai-ya!
花で一つ、鳥で二つ
One for flowers, two for birds
手打ち鳴らす
Clap your hands
風で三つ、嗚呼、月出て四つ
Three for the wind, ah, four when the moon rises
鳴らす鳴らす……
Ringing and ringing...
花で一つ、鳥で二つ
One for flowers, two for birds
手打ち鳴らす
Clap your hands
風で三つ、嗚呼、月出て四つ
Three for the wind, ah, four when the moon rises
鳴らす鳴らす
Ringing and ringing
今！
Now!
回レ！回レ！回レ！回レ！回レ！回レ！回レ！回レ！回レ！
Spin! Spin! Spin! Spin! Spin! Spin! Spin! Spin! Spin!
華麗に花弁 散らすように
Like petals scattering brilliantly
回レ！回レ！回レ！回レ！回レ！回レ！回レ！回レ！回レ！
Spin! Spin! Spin! Spin! Spin! Spin! Spin! Spin! Spin!
髪も振り乱して
With hair flying wildly
一昨日、昨日、今日と明日と明後日と
The day before yesterday, yesterday, today, tomorrow, and the day after
この宴は続く
This banquet continues
踊レ、歌エ、一心不乱に回レ
Dance, sing, spin with all your heart
今宵は何曜日か？
What day of the week is it tonight?
水木金？
Wed-Thu-Fri?
土日月火？
Sat-Sun-Mon-Tue?
ハッ、ハッ、ハッ、ハッ、ハッ、ハッ、ハッ、ハッ、ハイッヤ！
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Hai-ya!
ハッ、ハッ、ハッ、ハッ、よーっ、ポン！
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Yo, pon!
はい！ということで、3曲お送りいたしました！
Yes! And with that, we performed three songs!
まずは「檄！帝国華撃団」ということで
First was "Geki! Teikoku Kagekidan."
やっぱ和っぽいなんか曲ないかなと思って
I was looking for some Japanese-style songs,
色々探して、あ、この曲歌いたいなと思って今日はこの衣装で歌わせていただきました。
and I thought, "Ah, I want to sing this!" So I sang it in this outfit today.
そしてね、和っぽく扇子なんかもね、こうやって使ってみました。
And to add to the Japanese feel, I tried using a folding fan like this.
どうだったかな、なかなかね、こういう演出とかもできないので今日は色んな演出をしてみております。
How was it? We don't get to do this kind of production often, so I'm trying various things today.
ということで、えー次は、「夢想歌」をゲスト、フブちゃんと一緒に歌いました。
So, next, I sang "Musoka" with our guest, Fubu-chan.
「夢想歌」フブちゃんと、ま、フブちゃんと一緒にライブしたいなってのもあったので、
I've always wanted to do a live performance of "Musoka" with Fubu-chan,
今回ねフブちゃんお誘いして大好きな「夢想歌」という曲を歌いました。
so I invited her this time to sing one of my favorite songs.
そう、フブちゃんもね、一緒に歌ってくれる、踊ってくれるということで狐の、そうお面なんかもね使ったりして
Right, since Fubu-chan was going to sing and dance with me, we even used fox masks...
歌わせていただきました。どうだったかな、結構こだわりのお面外しとか、
How was it? We put a lot of effort into the part where we took off the masks.
頑張りました。えー次は、「回レ！雪月花」
We worked hard on it. Next up was "Maware! Setsugetsuka."
えーこちらは船長にも来ていただき、フブちゃんと、マリン船長と一緒にお送りしました。
Marine Senpai joined us for this one, and we performed it together with Fubu-chan.
この、「回レ！雪月花」は、2年前、2022年に、
As for "Maware! Setsugetsuka," two years ago in 2022...
えっと、船長とフブちゃんと一緒に歌ってみた、出しておりまして
I released a cover of it with Senpai and Fubu-chan.
たくさんたくさん再生いただいてありがとうございます。この、
Thank you so much for all the views. This...
この和のコンセプトライブで絶対にやりたいなと思っていたので、このライブで披露することができて嬉しい限りです。
I really wanted to do this at a Japanese-concept live, so I'm beyond happy we could perform it here.
めちゃくちゃね、あの歌詞とか、演出とか、こだわって作りました。ありがとう！
We put so much thought into the lyrics and the production. Thank you!
はい、ということで次がラストの曲になります！
Alright, so the next one will be the last song!
えー今来たばっかりー！
"Eh, I just got here!"
をやってライブですから。このあと、えー22時15分から
It's a live concert, after all. After this, starting from 22:15...
メンバー限定でアンコールライブがあります！
There will be an encore live performance for members only!
ぜひぜひ、あ、このライブいいなって思ってくれたらメンバーシップ入っていただけるととっても嬉しいです。
If you're enjoying this live, I'd be so happy if you joined the membership.
メンバーシップのアンコールライブでは、引き続き新衣装で和テイストの曲を歌っていきます。
In the membership encore live, I'll continue singing Japanese-style songs in this new outfit.
今までの雰囲気とちょっと違うね、曲をセレクトしたのでぜひぜひそちらもお楽しみに！
I've selected songs with a slightly different vibe than usual, so please look forward to that too!
ということで次がラストの曲ということなんですが、
And so, the next one is the final song, but...
本当に改めて活動6周年続けてこれたのは開拓者の皆さんの応援のおかげです。
Once again, it's thanks to all the Pioneers' support that I've been able to continue for six years.
今年はね、アルバム「Route IF」をリリースさせていただいたり、
This year, I was able to release the album "Route IF,"
そしてワンマンライブ「Chiral Entropy」も開催して、追加公演もさせていただいて本当に
and hold the one-man live "Chiral Entropy," including additional performances...
本当に本当に、
Truly, truly,
開拓者のみんなのパワーをめちゃくちゃいただいた、
I received so much power from all the Pioneers,
本当そんな年だったなって思います。
I think it was really that kind of year.
これからもたくさんみんなのことを、えー、楽し、
From now on, I'll keep doing my best...
みんなに楽しんでもらえるような配信だったり、歌だったりを頑張っていきたいと思います。
...to bring you streams and songs that you can all enjoy.
みんなが、えっと、元気に、元気に、
I want to be someone who can give everyone energy,
そして、ま、癒やし、癒やしを与えられる存在になりたいなって今後もそうなりたいなと思っていますので
and, well, become a presence that provides healing to you all.
これからも応援よろしくお願いします！
So please continue to support me!
はい。それでは、本当に本当に今日最後の曲です。
Alright. Now, this is truly the last song for today.
聴いてください。
Please listen.
渡月橋 ～君 想ふ～
Togetsukyo ~Kimi Omou~
寄り添う二人に 君がオーバーラップ
As the two of us drew close, you overlapped
色なき風に 思い馳せて
In the colorless wind, my thoughts drift to you
触れた手の温もり 今も
The warmth of your hand when we touched, even now...
Stop 時間を止めて
Stop, let time stand still
そう いつの日だって
Yes, no matter the day
君の言葉 忘れないよ
I won't forget your words
会いたい時に会えない
I can't see you when I want to
会いたい時に会えない 切なくて もどかしい
I can't see you when I want to, it's painful and frustrating
から紅に染まる渡月橋 導かれる日願って
The Togetsu Bridge stained in deep crimson, I pray for the day I'm led there
川の流れに祈りを込めて
Putting my prayers into the river's flow
I've been thinking about you, I've been thinking about you
いつも こころ 君のそば
Always, my heart is by your side
古の景色 変わりなく
The ancient scenery remains unchanged
今 この瞳に映し出す
Reflected in my eyes right now
彩りゆく季節 越えて
Crossing through the seasons as they color
Stock 覚えてますか?
Stock, do you remember?
ねぇ いつになったら
Hey, when will it be...
また巡り会えるのかな
...that we can meet again?
会いたい時に会えない
I can't see you when I want to
会いたい時に会えない この胸を焦がすの
I can't see you when I want to, it scorches my heart
から紅に水くくるとは 君との想いつなげて
The deep crimson waters, connecting my thoughts of you
川の流れに祈りを込めて
Putting my prayers into the river's flow
I've been thinking about you, I've been thinking about you
いつも 君を 探してる
I'm always searching for you
君となら不安さえ どんな時も消えていくよ
With you, even my anxiety disappears anytime
いつになったら優しく抱きしめられるのかな
I wonder when I'll be able to be held gently
から紅の紅葉たちさえ 熱い思いを告げては
Even the deep crimson autumn leaves, telling of hot passion
ゆらり揺れて歌っています
Swaying gently as they sing
I've been thinking about you, I've been thinking about you
いつも いつも 君想ふ
Always, always, thinking of you
AZKi 6th Anniversary LIVE 百花繚乱
AZKi 6th Anniversary LIVE 'Hyakka Ryouran'
AZKi活動6周年記念ライブ「百花繚乱」をご視聴いただきありがとうございました。
Thank you very much for watching AZKi's 6th Anniversary Live 'Hyakka Ryouran'.
いろんな花が咲き乱れていましたでしょうか？
Were various flowers in full bloom?
ということで最後に、お知らせを3つします！
And so, finally, I have three announcements to make!
1つ目は、アンコールライブについてです。
The first one is about the encore live.
この後22時15分からメンバー限定でアンコールライブを行います。
After this, from 22:15, we'll be having an encore live for members only.
ライブだけじゃなくて衣装の詳細も紹介しますので、お楽しみに。よろしくお願いします。
I'll be introducing details about the outfit as well as the live, so please look forward to it.
そして、2つ目はこちら！
And the second one is this!
グッズが出まーす！
Merchandise is coming out!
活動6周年記念グッズ。フルセットはこんな感じです。
6th Anniversary Merchandise. The full set looks like this.
今回のグッズコンセプトは「和風でお出かけ」です。1つずつ見ていきましょう。
The concept for this merchandise is "Outing in Japanese style". Let's take a look at them one by one.
まずは、こちら。
First, this one.
卓上屏風！
Desktop Folding Screen!
デスク、棚などに立てて飾れる和風イラストグッズ。
A Japanese-style illustration item that can be displayed on a desk, shelf, etc.
雨の日に和服でお出かけしているキービジュアルを屏風にしてみました。
I've made the key visual of going out in Japanese clothes on a rainy day into a folding screen.
イラストレーターは、Hitenさん。
The illustrator is Hiten-san.
幻想的な雰囲気のある感じに仕上げていただきました。
He finished it with a very fantastical atmosphere.
次は、こちら。
Next, this one.
つながる3連アクリルキーホルダー！
3-layer connecting acrylic keychain!
それぞれ1つのパーツだけでもチャームとして使えます。
Each part can be used as a charm on its own.
順番を変えても良し、別々で使っても良し。
You can change the order or use them separately.
イラストは、せんちゃさんに描いていただきました。
The illustrations were drawn by Sencha-san.
次は、こちら。
Next, this one.
開拓安全お守り！
Pioneer Safety Amulet!
手のひらサイズのお守りです。
It's a palm-sized amulet.
開拓安全の意味は、開拓者の安全を祈ることと、いろんな開拓、
'Pioneer safety' means praying for the safety of pioneers, and various 'pioneering',
新しい分野だったり領域や進路を切り開くという開拓の応援になったらいいなという気持ちを込めて作りました。
like opening up new fields, territories, or career paths. I made this to support such 'pioneering'.
次は、こちら。
Next, this one.
一緒に開拓！AZKiぬいぐるみパペット！
Pioneer together! AZKi Plushie Puppet!
帽子を被った、外ロケお出かけスタイルのパペットです。
It's a puppet in an outdoor location/outing style, wearing a hat.
男性の手のひらが入るぐらいのサイズ感を目指しました。
I aimed for a size that a man's palm can fit into.
イベントとかいろんなお出かけに連れて行ってくれたら嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you take it with you to events and various outings.
ラストは、こちら。
And last, this one.
ボイスが出まーす！
A voice pack is coming out!
内容は、雨の日に和服お正月衣装の私と君が相合傘をしながらお散歩するシチュエーションASMRボイスとなっております。
The content is a situation ASMR voice where you and I, in my New Year's Japanese outfit, take a walk under an umbrella on a rainy day.
雨音が聞こえる癒し系ASMRボイスを目指しました。
I aimed for a soothing ASMR voice where you can hear the sound of rain.
そして、今回もあります！
And we have it this time too!
フルセット購入特典はこちら！
The full set purchase bonus is this!
ポストカード！
Postcard!
キービジュアルと違い、笑顔のAZKiのポストカードです。
Unlike the key visual, it's a postcard of a smiling AZKi.
通常版は箔押しですが、数量限定で直筆サインもあります！
The regular version has foil stamping, but there are also handwritten signatures in limited quantities!
頑張って書きます！
I'll do my best to write them!
直筆サイン入りが欲しい方は早めにご購入ください。よろしくお願いします。
If you want a handwritten signature, please purchase early. Thank you.
さらに、今回は特典ボイスも付きます。
Furthermore, it comes with a bonus voice pack this time.
通常販売のボイスの少し後のシチュエーションASMRボイスです。
It's a situation ASMR voice pack set shortly after the regular one.
内容は散歩をしていたら雨が強くなってきたため、家に帰ることにした2人のやり取りです。
The content is the interaction between the two who decided to go home because the rain got stronger while walking.
通常販売ボイス、特典ボイスは別々でも楽しめますが、
You can enjoy the regular and bonus voice packs separately, but...
特典ボイスはより距離の近い、二人きり感を意識した内容になっています。
The bonus voice pack is designed to feel more intimate and like it's just the two of you.
傘はね、1つしかないからね。
Because, you see, there's only one umbrella.
雨が強くなったら濡れないように…みたいな感じです。
It's like... "let's make sure we don't get wet if the rain gets stronger."
そして、お知らせの3つ目！
And the third announcement!
こちらをご覧ください！
Please take a look at this!
月影揺れる夜の小道 ヒラリ舞い散る花の香り
Moonlight sways on the night path / The scent of flowers fluttering down
カラカラと鳴る風鈴の音 淡い夢がそっと囁く
The sound of the wind chime clattering / A faint dream softly whispers
影絵の中で踊る影 ゆらゆら揺れる灯りの下
Shadows dancing within the shadow play / Under the flickering lamp
彩り豊かな夕焼け空 キラリと光る星の砂
A colorful sunset sky / The glinting star sand
過ぎゆく季節、音もなく
The passing seasons, without a sound
心の奥に響く声
A voice echoing deep within my heart
カゲロウの調べに乗せて
Carried on the melody of the heat haze
君との記憶　消えないように
So that my memories with you will not fade
結び合う手が伝うぬくもり
The warmth transmitted through our clasped hands
この瞬間を永久に刻む
I'll carve this moment into eternity
ひらひらと舞う、夜風に乗せ
Dancing flutteringly, carried on the night breeze
共に歩んだ日々を感じて
Feeling the days we walked together
未来を描く　君と二人で
Drawing the future, just the two of us
今宵もまた光の中へ
Tonight again, into the light
ということで、AZKiの新曲「カゲロウの調べ」
And so, AZKi's new song, "Kagerou no Shirabe"...
11月16日土曜日、配信リリース決定！
...is set for digital release on Saturday, November 16th!
この後、11月16日土曜日0時から各配信サービスにて配信開始。
Starting from midnight on Saturday, November 16th,
it will be available on various streaming services.
さらに、11月16日土曜日21時からミュージックビデオ、YouTubeプレミア公開！
Furthermore, the music video will have its
YouTube premiere at 9:00 PM on Saturday, November 16th!
待機所はこの放送後、爆誕します！お楽しみに！
The waiting room will be created right after this broadcast!
Please look forward to it!
さらに、12月にも新曲あるかも？
And there might even be a new song in December?
ぜひこちらも、お楽しみに！
Please look forward to that as well!
以上、お知らせでした！
That's all for the announcements!
それでは、アンコールライブでお会いしましょう！
Well then, I'll see you at the encore live!
今日は、ありがとうございました！バイバーイ！
Thank you so much for today! Bye-bye!